LONNIE ALEXANDER ARNOLD

Colorado Springs, CO 80910 713-258-5588 | lonnie.a.arnold@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/alex-arnold1/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Information Technology Professional and U.S. Army Veteran leveraging 9 years of proven experience in Customer Service and IT and Equipment Maintenance. Possess a comprehensive background in maintenance and repair, implementing small and medium sized networks, configuration of routers & switches, technical support, assigning maintenance services, risk mitigation, and conflict resolution. Reputation for exceeding customer expectations, organizational skills, and attention to detail. Career supported by an associate degree and CompTIA Sec+ and A+ certifications.

- Customer Satisfaction
- Scheduling
- Network Configuration
- IT Support Services
- Python
- Trouble Ticket Resolution
- Linux OS
- Information Security
- Windows OS

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Technical Skills: Microsoft 365 | Intune | Networking | Wireshark | Active Directory | Routing & Switching CompTIA Security+ Certification | CompTIA | 01/2021 CompTIA A+ Certification | CompTIA | 02/2021

EDUCATION

Associate of Applied Science, Computer Networking – Cisco | Pikes Peak Community College | 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Harrison School District 2 | Colorado Springs, CO

Computer Support Technician, Technology Office, Sierra High School

Oversee school's Technology Office; respond to staff and student technical questions; troubleshoot and provide tech support.

- Managed >\$200K in IT equipment and supply inventory
- Created and resolved over 50 tickets per week with an average completion time of 72 hours in Web Help Desk for staff and students
- Reimaged computers, uploaded software & firmware updates, set up staff printers, and issued student laptops & hotspots
- Helped establish the E-Sports Team that competes in online video games
- Supported over 900 staff and students daily

Tek Experts USA | Colorado Springs, CO

Software Support Engineer, Microsoft Office 365 & Intune Teams

Provided Premier Tier 2 support for Enterprise clientele.

- In-depth knowledge of mail flows, product configuration, subscription limitations, and other skills to resolve cases
- Utilized Microsoft Virtual Machines (VMAS) to reproduce customer environments; ran diagnostics utilizing a variety of software tools (both open source and proprietary)
- Conducted research, vetting the information through valid sources and team collaboration

Pikes Peak Community College | Colorado Springs, CO Junior IT School Services (ITSS) Technician

11/2018 - 05/2020

05/2020 - 08/2020

08/2020 - Present

Completed daily assigned ITSS work requests and emergency requests in a timely and professional manner.

- As a Junior Tech, led a team of 5 employees
- Relocated/replaced IT equipment; installed and configured software
- Troubleshot computers, audio systems, projector systems, internet connectivity, phone systems, login issues, password resets, profile issues, document scanning issues, printing issues, and e-fax issues
- Assisted Tier 2 networking team with IDF management and wireless access point deployment
- Supported over 1500 staff and students daily

Thin Metal Parts | Colorado Springs, CO Quality Control Inspector, Quality Control Department

05/2018 - 12/2018

Followed quality control procedures to ensure metal parts met customer provided specifications; packaged and shipped parts.

- Inspected parts under microscope and with computer programmed machines to ensure 100% compliance
- Performed measurements on various parts using a micrometer ensuring consistent standards were met
- Checked parts in and out of inventory as well as verified inventory counts ensuring 100% accountability of inventory

United States Army - Various Locations

09/2011 - 08/2017

Small Arms Repair Shop Foreman | Small Arms and Towed Artillery Maintenance Technician, Armament Shop Supervised 4 personnel providing field and sustainment level support maintenance on \$2M in equipment, small arms, and weapons. Diagnosed and troubleshot malfunctions of small arms and other infantry weapons. Oversaw the disposition, evacuation and movement of all equipment requiring higher maintenance.

- Mentored and trained 4 team members on various small arms weapons, including how to check for defaults, perform root cause analysis to problems, and properly using hand and power tools
- Trained 5 Foreign Military personnel during 2nd deployment to Afghanistan providing them with weapon systems repair capability
- Key in saving unit \$500K by performing repairs instead of outsourcing to a 3rd party
- Created and managed maintenance schedules ensuring equipment readiness and minimizing downtime; prepared and administered maintenance work orders and ordered necessary parts
- Maintained 98% readiness rating on 500+ weapons and systems, ensuring availability for rapid deployment
- Directed employment of weapons systems; maintained 100% accountability & serviceability of assigned equipment
- Completed turn-in of all serviceable and non-serviceable parts; maintained the shipment of received parts
- Reputation for being the "Battalion's Go-to-Person" for any problems with the artillery or small arms

NOTABLE AWARDS

Army Commendation Medal (2) | Army Achievement Medal | National Defense Service Medal Afghanistan Campaign Medal with 2 Campaign Stars | NATO Service Medal